# TIFFANY FORKNER

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

443.994.1689 · tiffanv.forkner@gmail.com · Baltimore, MD · linkedln.com/in/tiffanvforkner · github.com/thetif

### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated Senior Software Engineer with 19+ years of experience developing web applications. Skilled in agile development, object oriented design, functional programming, automated testing, secure coding standards, refactoring legacy systems, mentoring team members, and driving technical change. Dedicated to producing quality software and supporting collaboration.

# **SKILLS**

JavaScript	React	MongoDB	Jest	MacOS	Git
TypeScript	Next.js	PostgreSQL	React Testing Library	Linux	GitHub
Python	Redux	MySQL	Playwright	UNIX	Jira
Ruby	React Hook Forms	SQLite	Cypress	Windows	ZenHub
HTML/CSS	Node.js	AmazonRDS	Mock Service Worker	AWS	VSCode
SQL	Express	Oracle	Mocha	Docker	Confluence
Golang	Angular	Elasticsearch	Pytest	Storybook	

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Fearless Solutions, LLC | Baltimore, MD | 7/2016 - Present

Project: CMS - OneMAC Upgrade (10/2024 – present)

- Developed a React web application with Lambda functions querying OpenSearch.
- Improved Vitest unit test coverage from 51.5% to 91.6% in less than 2 months.
- Created GitHub Actions to automatically publish testing reports and release notes to GitHub Pages site.
- Stack: React, TypeScript, Tailwind, AWS Lambda, OpenSearch, Vitest, Playwright, Bun, Mock Service Worker, Jekyll

**Project**: CDC - Data Exchange Upload API (8/2024 – 10/2024)

- Developed an API endpoint in Golang server to determine the upload status of files being uploaded to a tus server.
- Developed a file upload status tracker written in JavaScript, HTML, CSS using a tus client to display the upload status.
- Developed a tus client context for use in Playwright tests to allow for testing server functions from within Playwright tests.
- Stack: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Golang, TUS, Playwright, GitHub Actions

**Project**: SBA - The OII Rehoming Project (11/2023 – 8/2024)

- Led 2 teams of 2 engineers in modernization of multiple disparate legacy systems into a single application; supported team members, developed code, documented processes, ensured code quality, collaborated with cross functional team members, gathered requirements from clients, and steered technical direction.
- Improved the development process of one team by implementing **DevOps** standards including source control, code reviews, automated tests and scans, and automated deployment.
- Developed a Lambda function in Python to read messages off of an AWS SQS queue and process them into the system.
- Stack: Python, Pytest, AWS Lambda, AWS SQS, Java

Project: NFL - Football Operations Database (6/2023 - 10/2023)

- Led team of 3 engineers by architecting application using the latest industry standards, supporting team members, developing code, ensuring code quality, collaborating with cross functional team members, and steering technical direction.
- Stack: Next.js, React, TypeScript, Prisma, PostgreSQL, NextAuth.js, Okta, Tailwind, Headless UI, Storybook, Jest, React Testing Library, Mock Service Worker, Playwright

Project: CMS - MESHub (4/2023 - 11/2023)

• Led team of 5 engineers by ensuring project quality, collaborating with cross functional team members, gathering requirements, and managing the transition of the contract from the eAPD application to the new MESHub application with new team members, technologies, objectives, and users.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (cont.)

Project: CMS - Electronic Advanced Planning Document (7/2020 – 4/2023)

- Led team of 5 engineers in developing a **React** web application with a **Node.js** backend; assigned work, contributed code, supported team members, ensured code quality, documented processes, participated in user research sessions, and maintained road map focus.
- Re-architected code to use **Okta** for authentication and acted as a liaison with the CMS Okta team.
- Moved large JSON objects from a PostgreSQL database to MongoDB to provide faster speeds, more flexibility in queries, and more efficient updates of the data.
- Stack: React, Redux, React Hook Forms, Sass, Webpack, Node.js, Express, Knex, PostgreSQL, Mongoose, MongoDB, Okta,
   Cypress, Jest, React Testing Library

Project: DIA - Intelligence Mission Data Management, Analysis, and Reporting System (7/2017 – 7/2020)

- Developed a React web application with Node.js microservices following the command-query (CQRS) model using RabbitMQ to communicate between services.
- Maintained Ruby script for ingesting data from 3rd party sources.
- Led the adoption of automated testing using Cypress, React Testing Library, and Jest.
- Stack: React, Redux, Sass, Webpack, Node.js, Express, Java, RabbitMQ, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Mongoose, MongoDB, Ruby,
   Cypress, React Testing Library, Jest

**Project**: NY Harbor Foundation - Billion Oyster Project (7/2016 – 9/2017)

- Led team of 2 in daily stand-ups, sprint planning, sprint reviews, and retrospectives.
- Developed an Angular web application with a Node.js backend.
- Stack: Angular, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mocha, Protractor

### **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

CyberPoint International | Baltimore, MD | 2/2015 – 6/2016

- Developed an Angular web application with a Node.js backend.
- Used Google Maps API and Mapbox for geolocating addresses inside bounding boxes.
- Stack: Angular, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Google Maps API, Mapbox, Mocha

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Fearless Solutions, LLC | Baltimore, MD | 8/2013 - 9/2014

- Initiated complete refactoring of a single-page, 3.5k line, legacy application written in Java, including restructuring code into
  an MVC architecture, moving hard-coded values to a configuration database, and adding unit and integration tests using
  JUnit.
- Created an **ExtJS** web application to manage the configurations in the database, view dynamically generated time series charts, export the PNG version of the charts, and export CSV reports.
- Stack: Java, JPA, Oracle, Maven, Spring, ExtJS, JUnit

# EARLY PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER	Harris   Annapolis Junction, MD   7/2011 - 8/2013
SOFTWARE ENGINEER	Fearless Solutions, LLC   Baltimore, MD   10/2010 – 7/2011
SOFTWARE ENGINEER	eDaptive Systems   Baltimore, MD   11/2006 – 9/2007
SOFTWARE ENGINEER	Euler Hermes ACI   Owings Mills, MD   6/2006 – 11/2006
SOFTWARE ENGINEER	Turner Broadcasting Systems   Atlanta, GA   2/2005 – 3/2006

#### **EDUCATION**

MASTER'S DEGREE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY | University of Maryland Global Campus, Online

2008 - 2010

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

1999 - 2004